A Guide to the Additional Papers of the Randolph Family of Edgehill ca. 1866-1967,n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of the Randolph Family of Edgehill ca.1866-1967,n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
This collection consists of ca. 15 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was loaned to the Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library by Stevens M. Moyer, 751 Seneca Parkway, Rochester, New York 14613, on December 2, 2005.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Randolph family, one of the earliest and most important families to settle in Virginia in 1673 were landowners, lawyers, congressman, and several held high office in the state of Virginia and the United States Government. Thomas Jefferson, third President of the United States, was a member of the Randolph family. The Cary, Taylor, Kirk and Dickins' families were relations of the Randolph family.
Scope and Content
This collection contains ca.15 items ca.1866-1967, n.d.,and consists of genealogies of the Randolph [1700-1911], Taylor, Kirk and Dickins' families with some additional information on the Cary Family [1180- 1830]; including a narrative sketch of a man named Augustus (Augustine) Herrman (1605-1686). There are also some handwritten biographical notes about Thomas Jefferson; his father, Peter Jefferson; a contemporary of his father's, William Byrd and a former congressman, William Nelson.
In addition to the genealogies, there is a miscellaneous household inventory list with a note outlining certain tasks of an estate administration such as: a burial; and collection and payment of debts. There is also a transcription of tombstone inscriptions for the Randolph family.
There are two medals in this collection. One is a University of Virginia Medal given to Stevens Mason Taylor (great-great grandson of Thomas Jefferson) because he was a student at the University and fought in the Civil War. The other was awarded to Edwin Kirk (husband of Page Taylor) for meritorious service by the Department of the Interior on December 31, 1954.
Arrangement
This collection is organized by topic in alphabetical order.
Contents List
- Cary Family Genealogy [1180-1830] n.d. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Augustus (Augustine) Herrman (1605-1686) n.d. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Jefferson Genealogy and notes on William Byrd and William Nelson (1674-1826) n.d. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Kirk miscellaneous genealogy 1967, May 12 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Miscellaneous inventory lists n.d. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Randolph genealogy including notes by Margaret Harvie Dickins [1700-1911] n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
- John Charles Randolph Taylor n.d. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Transcriptions of Tombstone inscriptions (Randolph's) [1771] (Box-folder 1:8)
- United States Department of the Interior medal to Edwin Kirk n.d., minitray
- University of Virginia medal to Stevens Mason Taylor 1954